<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet href="../xsl/codeSystem2html.xsl" type="text/xsl"?>
<?oxygen SCHSchema="vocab.sch"?>
<codeSystem xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:hl7-org:v3 vocab.xsd" xmlns="urn:hl7-org:v3">
      <name>ParticipationFunction</name>
      <desc>This code is used to specify the exact function an actor had in a service in all necessary detail. This domain may include local
            extensions (CWE).</desc>
      <code code="WEPDGEM" codeSystem="2.16.840.1.113883.5.88" displayName="Gemachtigde volgens Wet op het EPD"/>
      <!-- _AuthorizedParticipationFunction 
            This code is used to specify the exact function an actor is authorized to have in a service in all necessary detail.
      -->
      <!--
            1-A	. _AuthorizedReceiverParticipationFunction
            This code is used to specify the exact function an actor is authorized to have as a receiver of information that is the subject of a consent directive or consent override.
      -->
      <code code="AUCG" codeSystem="2.16.840.1.113883.5.88" displayName="caregiver information receiver">
            <originalText>Description:Caregiver authorized to receive patient health information.</originalText>
      </code>


      <code code="AULR" codeSystem="2.16.840.1.113883.5.88" displayName="legitimate relationship information receiver">
            <originalText>Description:Provider with legitimate relationship authorized to receive patient health information.</originalText>
      </code>

      <code code="AUTM" codeSystem="2.16.840.1.113883.5.88" displayName="care team information receiver">
            <originalText>Description:Member of care team authorized to receive patient health information.</originalText>
      </code>

      <code code="AUWA" codeSystem="2.16.840.1.113883.5.88" displayName="work area information receiver">
            <originalText>Description:Entities within specified work area authorized to receive patient health information.</originalText>
      </code>

      <!-- 
            _ConsenterParticipationFunction
            This code is used to specify the exact function an actor is authorized to have in authoring a consent directive.
      -->
      <code code="GRDCON" codeSystem="2.16.840.1.113883.5.88" displayName="legal guardian consent author">
            <originalText>Description:Legal guardian of the subject of consent authorized to author a consent directive for the subject of
                  consent.</originalText>
      </code>

      <code code="POACON" codeSystem="2.16.840.1.113883.5.88" displayName="healthcare power of attorney consent author">
            <originalText>Description:Person authorized with healthcare power of attorney to author a consent directive for the subject of
                  consent.</originalText>
      </code>

      <code code="PRCON" codeSystem="2.16.840.1.113883.5.88" displayName="personal representative consent author">
            <originalText>Description:Personal representative of the subject of consent authorized to author a consent directive for the subject of
                  consent.</originalText>
      </code>

      <code code="PROMSK" codeSystem="2.16.840.1.113883.5.88" displayName="authorized provider masking author">
            <originalText>Definition:Provider authorized to mask information to protect the patient, a third party, or to ensure that the provider has
                  consulted with the patient prior to release of this information.</originalText>
      </code>

      <code code="SUBCON" codeSystem="2.16.840.1.113883.5.88" displayName="subject of consent author">
            <originalText>Description:Subject of consent authorized to author a consent directive.</originalText>
      </code>

      <!--
            _OverriderParticipationFunction
            This code is used to specify the exact function an actor is authorized to have in authoring a consent override.
      -->

      <code code="AUCOV" codeSystem="2.16.840.1.113883.5.88" displayName="consent overrider">
            <originalText>Description:Entity authorized to override a consent directive.</originalText>
      </code>

      <code code="AUEMROV" codeSystem="2.16.840.1.113883.5.88" displayName="emergency overrider">
            <originalText>Description:Entity authorized to override a consent directive or privacy policy in an emergency.</originalText>
      </code>
      <!-- 
            _CoverageParticipationFunction
            Definition: Set of codes indicating the manner in which sponsors, underwriters, and payers participate in a policy or program.
      -->
      <!-- 
            _PayorParticipationFunction
            Definition: Set of codes indicating the manner in which payors participate in a policy or program.
      -->
      <code code="CLMADJ" codeSystem="2.16.840.1.113883.5.88" displayName="claims adjudication">
            <originalText>Definition: Manages all operations required to adjudicate fee for service claims or managed care encounter
                  reports.</originalText>
      </code>

      <code code="ENROLL" codeSystem="2.16.840.1.113883.5.88" displayName="enrollment broker">
            <originalText>Definition: Managing the enrollment of covered parties.</originalText>
      </code>

      <code code="FFSMGT" codeSystem="2.16.840.1.113883.5.88" displayName="ffs management">
            <originalText>Definition: Managing all operations required to administer a fee for service or indemnity health plan including enrolling
                  covered parties and providing customer service, provider contracting, claims payment, care management and utilization
                  review.</originalText>
      </code>

      <code code="MCMGT" codeSystem="2.16.840.1.113883.5.88" displayName="managed care management">
            <originalText>Definition: Managing all operations required to administer a managed care plan including enrolling covered parties and
                  providing customer service,, provider contracting, claims payment, care management and utilization review.</originalText>
      </code>

      <code code="PROVMGT" codeSystem="2.16.840.1.113883.5.88" displayName="provider management">
            <originalText>Definition: Managing provider contracting, provider services, credentialing, profiling, performance measures, and ensuring
                  network adequacy.</originalText>
      </code>

      <code code="UMGT" codeSystem="2.16.840.1.113883.5.88" displayName="utilization management">
            <originalText>Definition: Managing utilization of services by ensuring that providers adhere to, e.g., payeraTMs clinical protocols for
                  medical appropriateness and standards of medical necessity. May include management of authorizations for services and
                  referrals.</originalText>
      </code>
      <!--
            . _SponsorParticipationFunction
            Definition: Set of codes indicating the manner in which sponsors participate in a policy or program. NOTE: use only when the Sponsor is not further specified with a SponsorRoleType as being either a fully insured sponsor or a self insured sponsor.
      -->

      <code code="FULINRD" codeSystem="2.16.840.1.113883.5.88" displayName="fully insured">
            <originalText>Definition: Responsibility taken by a sponsor to contract with one or more underwriters for the assumption of full
                  responsibility for the risk and administration of a policy or program.</originalText>
      </code>

      <code code="SELFINRD" codeSystem="2.16.840.1.113883.5.88" displayName="self insured">
            <originalText>Definition: Responsibility taken by a sponsor to organize the underwriting of risk and administration of a policy or
                  program.</originalText>
      </code>

      <!-- 
            _UnderwriterParticipationFunction
            Definition: Set of codes indicating the manner in which underwriters participate in a policy or program.
      -->

      <code code="PAYORCNTR" codeSystem="2.16.840.1.113883.5.88" displayName="payor contracting">
            <originalText>Definition: Contracting for the provision and administration of health services to payors while retaining the risk for
                  coverage. Contracting may be for all provision and administration; or for provision of certain types of services; for provision of
                  services by region; and by types of administration, e.g., claims adjudication, enrollment, provider management, and utilization
                  management. Typically done by underwriters for sponsors who need coverage provided to covered parties in multiple regions. The
                  underwriter may act as the payor in some, but not all of the regions in which coverage is provided.</originalText>
      </code>

      <code code="REINS" codeSystem="2.16.840.1.113883.5.88" displayName="reinsures">
            <originalText>Definition: Underwriting reinsurance for another underwriter for the policy or program.</originalText>
      </code>

      <code code="RETROCES" codeSystem="2.16.840.1.113883.5.88" displayName="retrocessionaires">
            <originalText>Definition: Underwriting reinsurance for another reinsurer.</originalText>
      </code>

      <code code="SUBCTRT" codeSystem="2.16.840.1.113883.5.88" displayName="subcontracting risk">
            <originalText>Definition: Delegating risk for a policy or program to one or more subcontracting underwriters, e.g., a major health insurer
                  may delegate risk for provision of coverage under a national health plan to other underwriters by region .</originalText>
      </code>

      <code code="UNDERWRTNG" codeSystem="2.16.840.1.113883.5.88" displayName="underwriting">
            <originalText>Definition: Provision of underwriting analysis for another underwriter without assumption of risk.</originalText>
      </code>

      <code code="ADMPHYS" codeSystem="2.16.840.1.113883.5.88" displayName="admitting physician">
            <originalText>A physician who admitted a patient to a hospital or other care unit that is the context of this service.</originalText>
      </code>

      <code code="ANEST" codeSystem="2.16.840.1.113883.5.88" displayName="anesthesist">
            <originalText>In a typical anesthesia setting an anesthesiologist or anesthesia resident in charge of the anesthesia and life support, but
                  only a witness to the surgical procedure itself. To clarify responsibilities anesthesia should always be represented as a separate
                  service related to the surgery.</originalText>
      </code>

      <code code="ANRS" codeSystem="2.16.840.1.113883.5.88" displayName="anesthesia nurse">
            <originalText>In a typical anesthesia setting the nurse principally assisting the anesthesiologist during the critical
                  periods.</originalText>
      </code>

      <code code="ATTPHYS" codeSystem="2.16.840.1.113883.5.88" displayName="attending physician">
            <originalText>A physician who is primarily responsible for a patient during the hospitalization, which is the context of the
                  service.</originalText>
      </code>

      <code code="DISPHYS" codeSystem="2.16.840.1.113883.5.88" displayName="discharging physician">
            <originalText>A physician who discharged a patient from a hospital or other care unit that is the context of this service.</originalText>
      </code>

      <code code="FASST" codeSystem="2.16.840.1.113883.5.88" displayName="first assistant surgeon">
            <originalText>In a typical surgery setting the assistant facing the primary surgeon. The first assistant performs parts of the operation
                  and assists in others (e.g., incision, approach, electrocoutering, ligatures, sutures).</originalText>
      </code>

      <code code="MDWF" codeSystem="2.16.840.1.113883.5.88" displayName="midwife">
            <originalText>A person (usually female) helping a woman deliver a baby. Responsibilities vary locally, ranging from a mere optional
                  assistant to a full required participant, responsible for (normal) births and pre- and post-natal care for both mother and
                  baby.</originalText>
      </code>

      <code code="NASST" codeSystem="2.16.840.1.113883.5.88" displayName="nurse assistant">
            <originalText>In a typical surgery setting the non-sterile nurse handles material supply from the stock, forwards specimen to pathology,
                  and helps with other non-sterile tasks (e.g., phone calls, etc.).</originalText>
      </code>

      <code code="PCP" codeSystem="2.16.840.1.113883.5.88" displayName="primary care physician">
            <originalText>The healthcare provider that holds primary responsibility for the overall care of a patient.</originalText>
      </code>

      <code code="PRISURG" codeSystem="2.16.840.1.113883.5.88" displayName="primary surgeon">
            <originalText>In a typical surgery setting the primary performing surgeon.</originalText>
      </code>

      <code code="RNDPHYS" codeSystem="2.16.840.1.113883.5.88" displayName="rounding physician">
            <originalText>A physician who made rounds on a patient in a hospital or other care center.</originalText>
      </code>

      <code code="SASST" codeSystem="2.16.840.1.113883.5.88" displayName="second assistant surgeon">
            <originalText>In a typical surgery setting the assistant who primarily holds the hooks.</originalText>
      </code>

      <code code="SNRS" codeSystem="2.16.840.1.113883.5.88" displayName="scrub nurse">
            <originalText>In a typical surgery setting the nurse in charge of the instrumentation.</originalText>
      </code>

      <code code="TASST" codeSystem="2.16.840.1.113883.5.88" displayName="third assistant">
            <originalText>In a typical surgery setting there is rarely a third assistant (e.g., in some Hip operations the third assistant postures
                  the affected leg).</originalText>
      </code>
</codeSystem>
