<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../xsl/codeSystem2html.xsl"?><?oxygen SCHSchema="vocab.sch?>
<codeSystem xmlns:mif2="urn:hl7-org:v3/mif2" xmlns="urn:hl7-org:v3" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
   xmlns:ns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:hl7-org:v3 vocab.xsd" codeStrength="CWE">
   <name>ParticipationType</name>
   <desc/>
   <code code="PART" codeSystem="2.16.840.1.113883.5.90" displayName="Participation">
      <!-- v:ParticipationParticipation -->
      <originalText>Definition: Indicates that the target of the participation is involved in some manner in the act, but does not qualify
         how.</originalText>
   </code>
   <!-- 1-A _ParticipationAncillary (v:ParticipationAncillary)-->
   <code code="ADM" codeSystem="2.16.840.1.113883.5.90" displayName="admitter">
      <originalText>Definition: The practitioner who is responsible for admitting a patient to a patient encounter.</originalText>
   </code>
   <code code="ATND" codeSystem="2.16.840.1.113883.5.90" displayName="attender">
      <originalText>Definition: The practitioner that has responsibility for overseeing a patient's care during a patient encounter.</originalText>
   </code>
   <code code="CALLBCK" codeSystem="2.16.840.1.113883.5.90" displayName="callback contact">
      <originalText>Definition: A person or organization who should be contacted for follow-up questions about the act in place of the
         author.</originalText>
   </code>
   <code code="CON" codeSystem="2.16.840.1.113883.5.90" displayName="consultant">
      <originalText>Definition: An advisor participating in the service by performing evaluations and making recommendations.</originalText>
   </code>
   <code code="DIS" codeSystem="2.16.840.1.113883.5.90" displayName="discharger">
      <originalText>Definition: The practitioner who is responsible for the discharge of a patient from a patient encounter.</originalText>
   </code>
   <code code="ESC" codeSystem="2.16.840.1.113883.5.90" displayName="escort">
      <originalText>Definition: Only with Transportation services. A person who escorts the patient.</originalText>
   </code>
   <code code="REF" codeSystem="2.16.840.1.113883.5.90" displayName="referrer">
      <originalText>Definition: A person having referred the subject of the service to the performer (referring physician). Typically, a referring
         physician will receive a report.</originalText>
   </code>
   <!-- 1-A _ParticipationInformationGenerator (v:ParticipationInformationGenerator)-->
   <code code="AUT" codeSystem="2.16.840.1.113883.5.90" displayName="author (originator)">
      <originalText>Definition: Definition: A party that originates the Act and therefore has responsibility for the information given in the Act and
         ownership of this Act.</originalText>
   </code>
   <code code="INF" codeSystem="2.16.840.1.113883.5.90" displayName="informant">
      <originalText>Definition: A source of reported information (e.g., a next of kin who answers questions about the patient's history). For history
         questions, the patient is logically an informant, yet the informant of history questions is implicitly the subject.</originalText>
   </code>
   <code code="TRANS" codeSystem="2.16.840.1.113883.5.90" displayName="Transcriber">
      <!-- v:ParticipationInformationTranscriber -->
      <originalText>Definition: An entity entering the data into the originating system. The data entry entity is collected optionally for internal
         quality control purposes. This includes the transcriptionist for dictated text transcribed into electronic form.</originalText>
   </code>
   <code code="ENT" codeSystem="2.16.840.1.113883.5.90" displayName="data entry person">
      <originalText>Definition: A person entering the data into the originating system. The data entry person is collected optionally for internal
         quality control purposes. This includes the transcriptionist for dictated text.</originalText>
   </code>
   <code code="WIT" codeSystem="2.16.840.1.113883.5.90" displayName="witness">
      <originalText>Definition: Only with service events. A person witnessing the action happening without doing anything. A witness is not
         necessarily aware, much less approves of anything stated in the service event. Example for a witness is students watching an operation or an
         advanced directive witness.</originalText>
   </code>
   <code code="CST" codeSystem="2.16.840.1.113883.5.90" displayName="custodian">
      <originalText>Definition: An entity (person, organization or device) that is in charge of maintaining the information of this act (e.g., who
         maintains the report or the master service catalog item, etc.).</originalText>
   </code>
   <code code="DIR" codeSystem="2.16.840.1.113883.5.90" displayName="direct target">
      <!-- v:ParticipationTargetDirect -->
      <originalText>Definition: Target that is substantially present in the service and which is directly affected by the service action (includes
         consumed material, devices, etc.).</originalText>
   </code>
   <code code="BBY" codeSystem="2.16.840.1.113883.5.90" displayName="baby">
      <originalText>Definition: In an obstetric service, the baby.</originalText>
   </code>
   <code code="CSM" codeSystem="2.16.840.1.113883.5.90" displayName="consumable">
      <originalText>Definition: Target that is taken up, is diminished, and disappears in the service.</originalText>
   </code>
   <code code="DEV" codeSystem="2.16.840.1.113883.5.90" displayName="device">
      <!-- v:ParticipationTargetDevice -->
      <originalText>Definition: Something used in delivering the service without being substantially affected by the service (i.e. durable or inert
         with respect to that particular service). Examples are: monitoring equipment, tools, but also access/drainage lines, prostheses, pace maker,
         etc.</originalText>
   </code>
   <code code="NRD" codeSystem="2.16.840.1.113883.5.90" displayName="non-reuseable device">
      <originalText>Definition: A device that changes ownership due to the service, e.g., a pacemaker, a prosthesis, an insulin injection equipment
         (pen), etc. Such material may need to be restocked after he service.</originalText>
   </code>
   <code code="RDV" codeSystem="2.16.840.1.113883.5.90" displayName="reusable device">
      <originalText>Definition: A device that does not change ownership due to the service, i.e., a surgical instrument or tool or an endoscope. The
         distinction between reuseable and non-reuseable must be made in order to know whether material must be re-stocked.</originalText>
   </code>
   <code code="DON" codeSystem="2.16.840.1.113883.5.90" displayName="donor">
      <originalText>Definition: In some organ transplantation services and rarely in transfusion services a donor will be a target participant in the
         service. However, in most cases transplantation is decomposed in three services: explantation, transport, and implantation. The identity of
         the donor (recipient) is often irrelevant for the explantation (implantation) service.</originalText>
   </code>
   <code code="EXPAGNT" codeSystem="2.16.840.1.113883.5.90" displayName="ExposureAgent">
      <originalText>Definition: Description: The entity playing the associated role is the physical (including energy), chemical or biological
         substance that is participating in the exposure. For example in communicable diseases, the associated playing entity is the disease causing
         pathogen.</originalText>
   </code>
   <code code="EXPART" codeSystem="2.16.840.1.113883.5.90" displayName="ExposureParticipation">
      <!-- v:ParticipationExposureparticipation -->
      <originalText>Definition: Description:Direct participation in an exposure act where it is unknown that the participant is the source or subject
         of the exposure. If the participant is known to be the contact of an exposure then the SBJ participation type should be used. If the
         participant is known to be the source then the EXSRC participation type should be used.</originalText>
   </code>
   <code code="EXPTRGT" codeSystem="2.16.840.1.113883.5.90" displayName="ExposureTarget">
      <originalText>Definition: Description: The entity playing the associated role is the target (contact) of exposure.</originalText>
   </code>
   <code code="EXSRC" codeSystem="2.16.840.1.113883.5.90" displayName="ExposureSource">
      <originalText>Definition: Description:The entity playing the associated role is the source of exposure.</originalText>
   </code>
   <code code="PRD" codeSystem="2.16.840.1.113883.5.90" displayName="product">
      <originalText>Definition: A material target that is brought forth (produced) in the service (e.g., specimen in a specimen collection, access or
         drainage in a placement service, medication package in a dispense service). It doesn't matter whether the material produced had existence
         prior to the service, or whether it is created in the service (e.g., in supply services the product is taken from a stock).</originalText>
   </code>
   <code code="SBJ" codeSystem="2.16.840.1.113883.5.90" displayName="subject">
      <!-- v:ParticipationTargetSubject -->
      <originalText>Definition: The principle target that the service acts on. E.g. the patient in physical examination, a specimen in a lab
         observation. May also be a patient's family member (teaching) or a device or room (cleaning, disinfecting, housekeeping). Note: not all
         direct targets are subjects, consumables, and devices used as tools for a service are not subjects. However, a device may be a subject of a
         maintenance service.</originalText>
   </code>
   <code code="SPC" codeSystem="2.16.840.1.113883.5.90" displayName="specimen">
      <originalText>Definition: The subject of non-clinical (e.g. laboratory) observation services is a specimen.</originalText>
   </code>
   <code code="IND" codeSystem="2.16.840.1.113883.5.90" displayName="indirect target">
      <!-- v:ParticipationIndirectTarget -->
      <originalText>Definition: Target that is not substantially present in the act and which is not directly affected by the act, but which will be a
         focus of the record or documentation of the act.</originalText>
   </code>
   <code code="BEN" codeSystem="2.16.840.1.113883.5.90" displayName="beneficiary">
      <originalText>Definition: Target on behalf of whom the service happens, but that is not necessarily present in the service. Can occur together
         with direct target to indicate that a target is both, as in the case where the patient is the indirect beneficiary of a service rendered to a
         family member, e.g. counseling or given home care instructions. This concept includes a participant, such as a covered party, who derives
         benefits from a service act covered by a coverage act.</originalText>
   </code>
   <code code="CAGNT" codeSystem="2.16.840.1.113883.5.90" displayName="causative agent">
      <originalText>Definition: Definition: A factor, such as a microorganism, chemical substance, or form of radiation, whose presence, excessive
         presence, or (in deficiency diseases) relative absence is essential, in whole or in part, for the occurrence of a condition.</originalText>
   </code>
   <code code="COV" codeSystem="2.16.840.1.113883.5.90" displayName="coverage target">
      <originalText>Definition: The target participation for an individual in a health care coverage act in which the target role is either the policy
         holder of the coverage, or a covered party under the coverage.</originalText>
   </code>
   <code code="GUAR" codeSystem="2.16.840.1.113883.5.90" displayName="guarantor party">
      <originalText>Definition: The target person or organization contractually recognized by the issuer as a participant who has assumed fiscal
         responsibility for another personaTMs financial obligations by guaranteeing to pay for amounts owed to a particular account</originalText>
   </code>
   <code code="HLD" codeSystem="2.16.840.1.113883.5.90" displayName="holder">
      <originalText>Definition: Participant who posses an instrument such as a financial contract (insurance policy) usually based on some agreement
         with the author.</originalText>
   </code>
   <code code="RCT" codeSystem="2.16.840.1.113883.5.90" displayName="record target">
      <originalText>Definition: The record target indicates whose medical record holds the documentation of this act. This is especially important
         when the subject of a service is not the patient himself.</originalText>
   </code>
   <code code="RCV" codeSystem="2.16.840.1.113883.5.90" displayName="receiver">
      <originalText>Definition: The person (or organization) who receives the product of an Act.</originalText>
   </code>
   <code code="IRCP" codeSystem="2.16.840.1.113883.5.90" displayName="information recipient">
      <!-- v:ParticipationInformationRecipient -->
      <originalText>Definition: A party, who may or should receive or who has recieved the Act or subsequent or derivative information of that Act.
         Information recipient is inert, i.e., independent of mood." Rationale: this is a generalization of a too diverse family that the definition
         can't be any more specific, and the concept is abstract so one of the specializations should be used.</originalText>
   </code>
   <code code="NOT" codeSystem="2.16.840.1.113883.5.90" displayName="ugent notification contact">
      <originalText>Definition: An information recipient to notify for urgent matters about this Act. (e.g., in a laboratory order, critical results
         are being called by phone right away, this is the contact to call; or for an inpatient encounter, a next of kin to notify when the patient
         becomes critically ill).</originalText>
   </code>
   <code code="PRCP" codeSystem="2.16.840.1.113883.5.90" displayName="primary information recipient">
      <originalText>Definition: Information recipient to whom an act statement is primarily directed. E.g., a primary care provider receiving a
         discharge letter from a hospitalist, a health department receiving information on a suspected case of infectious disease. Multiple of these
         participations may exist on the same act without requiring that recipients be ranked as primary vs. secondary.</originalText>
   </code>
   <code code="REFB" codeSystem="2.16.840.1.113883.5.90" displayName="Referred By">
      <originalText>Definition: A participant (e.g. provider) who has referred the subject of an act (e.g. patient).</originalText>
   </code>
   <code code="REFT" codeSystem="2.16.840.1.113883.5.90" displayName="Referred to">
      <originalText>Definition: The person who receives the patient</originalText>
   </code>
   <code code="TRC" codeSystem="2.16.840.1.113883.5.90" displayName="tracker">
      <originalText>Definition: A secondary information recipient, who receives copies (e.g., a primary care provider receiving copies of results as
         ordered by specialist).</originalText>
   </code>
   <code code="LOC" codeSystem="2.16.840.1.113883.5.90" displayName="location">
      <!-- v:ParticipationTargetLocation -->
      <originalText>Definition: The facility where the service is done. May be a static building (or room therein) or a moving location (e.g.,
         ambulance, helicopter, aircraft, train, truck, ship, etc.)</originalText>
   </code>
   <code code="DST" codeSystem="2.16.840.1.113883.5.90" displayName="destination">
      <originalText>Definition: The destination for services. May be a static building (or room therein) or a movable facility (e.g.,
         ship).</originalText>
   </code>
   <code code="ELOC" codeSystem="2.16.840.1.113883.5.90" displayName="entry location">
      <originalText>Definition: A location where data about an Act was entered.</originalText>
   </code>
   <code code="ORG" codeSystem="2.16.840.1.113883.5.90" displayName="origin">
      <originalText>Definition: The location of origin for services. May be a static building (or room therein) or a movable facility (e.g.,
         ship).</originalText>
   </code>
   <code code="RML" codeSystem="2.16.840.1.113883.5.90" displayName="remote">
      <originalText>Definition: Some services take place at multiple concurrent locations (e.g., telemedicine, telephone consultation). The location
         where the principal performing actor is located is taken as the primary location (LOC) while the other location(s) are considered
         "remote."</originalText>
   </code>
   <code code="VIA" codeSystem="2.16.840.1.113883.5.90" displayName="via">
      <originalText>Definition: For services, an intermediate location that specifies a path between origin an destination.</originalText>
   </code>
   <code code="PRF" codeSystem="2.16.840.1.113883.5.90" displayName="performer">
      <!-- v:ParticipationPhysicalPerformer -->
      <originalText>Definition: Definition: A person, non-person living subject, organization or device that who actually and principally carries out
         the action. Device should only be assigned as a performer in circumstances where the device is performing independent of human intervention.
         Need not be the principal responsible actor.</originalText>
   </code>
   <code code="DIST" codeSystem="2.16.840.1.113883.5.90" displayName="distributor">
      <originalText>Definition: Distributes material used in or generated during the act.</originalText>
   </code>
   <code code="PPRF" codeSystem="2.16.840.1.113883.5.90" displayName="primary performer">
      <originalText>Definition: The principal or primary performer of the act.</originalText>
   </code>
   <code code="SPRF" codeSystem="2.16.840.1.113883.5.90" displayName="secondary performer">
      <originalText>Definition: A person assisting in an act through his substantial presence and involvement This includes: assistants, technicians,
         associates, or whatever the job titles may be.</originalText>
   </code>
   <code code="RESP" codeSystem="2.16.840.1.113883.5.90" displayName="responsible party">
      <originalText>Definition: The person or organization that has primary responsibility for the act. The responsible party is not necessarily
         present in an action, but is accountable for the action through the power to delegate, and the duty to review actions with the performing
         actor after the fact. This responsibility may be ethical, legal, contractual, fiscal, or fiduciary in nature.</originalText>
   </code>
   <code code="VRF" codeSystem="2.16.840.1.113883.5.90" displayName="verifier">
      <!-- v:ParticipationVerifier -->
      <originalText>Definition: A person who verifies the correctness and appropriateness of the service (plan, order, event, etc.) and hence takes on
         accountability.</originalText>
   </code>
   <code code="AUTHEN" codeSystem="2.16.840.1.113883.5.90" displayName="authenticator">
      <originalText>Definition: A verifier who attests to the accuracy of an act, but who does not have privileges to legally authenticate the act. An
         example would be a resident physician who sees a patient and dictates a note, then later signs it. Their signature constitutes an
         authentication.</originalText>
   </code>
   <code code="LA" codeSystem="2.16.840.1.113883.5.90" displayName="legal authenticator">
      <originalText>Definition: A verifier who legally authenticates the accuracy of an act. An example would be a staff physician who sees a patient
         and dictates a note, then later signs it. Their signature constitutes a legal authentication.</originalText>
   </code>
</codeSystem>
