<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../xsl/codeSystem2html.xsl"?>
<?oxygen SCHSchema="vocab.sch"?>
<codeSystem xmlns:mif2="urn:hl7-org:v3/mif2" xmlns="urn:hl7-org:v3" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
    xmlns:ns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:hl7-org:v3 vocab.xsd" codeStrength="CNE">
    <name>ContextControl</name>
    <desc>A code that specifies how an ActRelationship or Participation contributes to the context of an Act, and whether it may be propagated to
        descendent Acts whose association allows such propagation (see also attributes Participation.contextControlCode,
        ActRelationship.contextControlCode, ActRelationship.contextConductionInd). </desc>
    <!-- 0-A _ContextControlAdditive (v:ContextControlAdditive)-->
    <code code="AN" codeSystem="2.16.840.1.113883.5.1057" displayName="additive, non-propagating">
        <originalText>Definition: The association adds to the existing context associated with the Act, but will not propagate 
            to any descendant Acts reached by conducting ActRelationships (see contextControlCode). Examples: If an 'Author' 
            Participation were marked as "Additive, Non-Propagating" it means that the author will be added to the set of author 
            participations that have propagated from ancestor Acts for the purpose of this Act. However only the previously 
            propagated authors will propagate to any child Acts that allow context to be propagated.</originalText>
    </code>
    <code code="AP" codeSystem="2.16.840.1.113883.5.1057" displayName="additive, propagating">
        <originalText>Definition: The association adds to the existing context associated with the Act, and will propagate to 
            any descendant Acts reached by conducting ActRelationships (see contextControlCode). Examples: If an 'Author' 
            Participation were marked as "Additive, Propagating" it means that the author will be added to the set of author 
            participations that have propagated from ancestor Acts, and will itself propagate with the other authors to any 
            child Acts that allow context to be propagated.</originalText>
    </code>
    <!-- 0-A _ContextControlNonPropagating (v:ContextControlNonPropagating)-->
    <code code="ON" codeSystem="2.16.840.1.113883.5.1057" displayName="overriding, non-propagating">
        <originalText>Definition: The association is added to the existing context associated with the Act, but overrides an 
            association with the same typeCode. However, this overriding association will not propagate to any descendant Acts 
            reached by conducting ActRelationships (see contextControlCode). Examples: If an 'Author' Participation were marked 
            as "Overriding, Non-Propagating" it means that the author will replace the set of author participations that have 
            propagated from ancestor Acts. Furthermore, no author participations whatsoever will propagate to any child Acts 
            that allow context to be propagated.</originalText>
    </code>
    <!-- 0-A _ContextControlOverriding (v:ContextControlOverriding)-->
    <code code="OP" codeSystem="2.16.840.1.113883.5.1057" displayName="overriding, propagating">
        <originalText>Definition: The association is added to the existing context associated with the Act, but overrides an 
            association with the same typeCode. This overriding association will propagate to any descendant Acts reached by 
            conducting ActRelationships (see contextControlCode). Examples: If an 'Author' Participation were marked as 
            "Overriding, Propagating" it means that the author will replace the set of author participations that have 
            propagated from ancestor Acts, and will itself be the only author to propagate to any child Acts that allow 
            context to be propagated.</originalText>
    </code>
    <!-- 0-A _ContextControlPropagating (v:ContextControlPropagating)-->
</codeSystem>
