<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type"text/xsl" href="../xsl/codeSystem2html.xsl"?>
<?oxygen SCHSchema="vocab.sch"?>
<codeSystem xmlns="urn:hl7-org:v3" xmlns:mif2="urn:hl7-org:v3/mif2" xmlns:ns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"
    xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" codeStrength="CWE" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:hl7-org:v3 vocab.xsd">
    <name>DocumentCompletion</name>
    <desc>Identifies the current completion state of a clinical document.</desc>
    <code code="AU" codeSystem="2.16.840.1.113883.5.33" displayName="authenticated">
        <originalText>Definition: A completion status in which a document has been signed manually or electronically by one or more individuals who
            attest to its accuracy. No explicit determination is made that the assigned individual has performed the authentication. While the
            standard allows multiple instances of authentication, it would be typical to have a single instance of authentication, usually by the
            assigned individual.</originalText>
    </code>
    <code code="DI" codeSystem="2.16.840.1.113883.5.33" displayName="dictated">
        <originalText>Definition: A completion status in which information has been orally recorded but not yet transcribed.</originalText>
    </code>
    <code code="DO" codeSystem="2.16.840.1.113883.5.33" displayName="documented">
        <originalText>Definition: A completion status in which document content, other than dictation, has been received but has not been translated
            into the final electronic format. Examples include paper documents, whether hand-written or typewritten, and intermediate electronic
            forms, such as voice to text.</originalText>
    </code>
    <code code="IN" codeSystem="2.16.840.1.113883.5.33" displayName="incomplete">
        <originalText>Definition: A completion status in which information is known to be missing from a transcribed document.</originalText>
    </code>
    <code code="IP" codeSystem="2.16.840.1.113883.5.33" displayName="in progress">
        <originalText>Definition: A workflow status where the material has been assigned to personnel to perform the task of transcription. The
            document remains in this state until the document is transcribed.</originalText>
    </code>
    <code code="LA" codeSystem="2.16.840.1.113883.5.33" displayName="legally authenticated">
        <originalText>Definition: A completion status in which a document has been signed manually or electronically by the individual who is legally
            responsible for that document. This is the most mature state in the workflow progression.</originalText>
    </code>
    <code code="PA" codeSystem="2.16.840.1.113883.5.33" displayName="pre-authenticated">
        <originalText>Definition: A completion status in which a document is transcribed but not authenticated.</originalText>
    </code>
</codeSystem>
