<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../xsl/codeSystem2html.xsl"?>
<?oxygen SCHSchema="vocab.sch"?>
<codeSystem xmlns:mif2="urn:hl7-org:v3/mif2" xmlns="urn:hl7-org:v3" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
   xmlns:ns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:hl7-org:v3 vocab.xsd" codeStrength="CWE">
   <name>ActClass</name>
   <desc/>
   <code code="ACT" codeSystem="2.16.840.1.113883.5.6" displayName="act">
      <!-- v:ActClassRoot -->
      <originalText>Definition: A record of something that is being done, has been done, can be done, or is intended or requested to be
         done.</originalText>
   </code>
   <code code="ACCM" codeSystem="2.16.840.1.113883.5.6" displayName="accommodation">
      <originalText>Definition: An accommodation is a service provided for a Person or other LivingSubject in which a place is provided for the
         subject to reside for a period of time. Commonly used to track the provision of ward, private and semi-private accommodations for a
         patient.</originalText>
   </code>
   <code code="ACCT" codeSystem="2.16.840.1.113883.5.6" displayName="account">
      <originalText>Definition: A financial account established to track the net result of financial acts.</originalText>
   </code>
   <code code="ACSN" codeSystem="2.16.840.1.113883.5.6" displayName="accession">
      <originalText>Definition: A unit of work, a grouper of work items as defined by the system performing that work. Typically some laboratory order
         fulfillers communicate references to accessions in their communications regarding laboratory orders. Often one or more specimens are related
         to an accession such that in some environments the accession number is taken as an identifier for a specimen (group).</originalText>
   </code>
   <code code="ADJUD" codeSystem="2.16.840.1.113883.5.6" displayName="financial adjudicationfinancial adjudication results&#xA;               ">
      <originalText>Definition: A transformation process where a requested invoice is transformed into an agreed invoice. Represents the adjudication
         processing of an invoice (claim). Adjudication results can be adjudicated as submitted, with adjustments or refused.</originalText>
   </code>
   <code code="CACT" codeSystem="2.16.840.1.113883.5.6" displayName="control act">
      <!-- v:ActClassControlAct -->
      <originalText>Definition: An act representing a system action such as the change of state of another act or the initiation of a query. All
         control acts represent trigger events in the HL7 context. ControlActs may occur in different moods.</originalText>
   </code>
   <code code="ACTN" codeSystem="2.16.840.1.113883.5.6" displayName="action">
      <originalText>Definition: Sender asks addressee to do something depending on the focal Act of the payload. An example is "fulfill this order".
         Addressee has responsibilities to either reject the message or to act on it in an appropriate way (specified by the specific receiver
         responsibilities for the interaction).</originalText>
   </code>
   <code code="INFO" codeSystem="2.16.840.1.113883.5.6" displayName="information">
      <originalText>Definition: Sender sends payload to addressee as information. Addressee does not have responsibilities beyond serving addressee's
         own interest (i.e., read and memorize if you see fit). This is equivalent to an FYI on a memo.</originalText>
   </code>
   <code code="STC" codeSystem="2.16.840.1.113883.5.6" displayName="state transition control">
      <originalText>Definition: Description: Sender transmits a status change pertaining to the focal act of the payload. This status of the focal act
         is the final state of the state transition. This can be either a request or an event, according to the mood of the control
         act.</originalText>
   </code>
   <code code="CNTRCT" codeSystem="2.16.840.1.113883.5.6" displayName="contract">
      <!-- v:ActClassContract -->
      <originalText>Definition: An agreement of obligation between two or more parties that is subject to contractual law and
         enforcement.</originalText>
   </code>
   <code code="FCNTRCT" codeSystem="2.16.840.1.113883.5.6" displayName="financial contract">
      <!-- v:ActClassFinancialContract -->
      <originalText>Definition: A contract whose value is measured in monetary terms.</originalText>
   </code>
   <code code="COV" codeSystem="2.16.840.1.113883.5.6" displayName="coverage">
      <originalText>Definition: When used in the EVN mood, this concept means with respect to a covered party:</originalText>
   </code>
   <code code="CONS" codeSystem="2.16.840.1.113883.5.6" displayName="consent">
      <originalText>Definition: The Consent class represents informed consents and all similar medico-legal transactions between the patient (or his
         legal guardian) and the provider. Examples are informed consent for surgical procedures, informed consent for clinical trials, advanced
         beneficiary notice, against medical advice decline from service, release of information agreement, etc.</originalText>
   </code>
   <code code="CONTREG" codeSystem="2.16.840.1.113883.5.6" displayName="container registration">
      <originalText>Definition: An Act where a container is registered either via an automated sensor, such as a barcode reader, or by manual
         receipt</originalText>
   </code>
   <code code="CTTEVENT" codeSystem="2.16.840.1.113883.5.6" displayName="clinical trial timepoint event">
      <originalText>Definition: An identified point during a clinical trial at which one or more actions are scheduled to be performed (definition
         mood), or are actually performed (event mood). The actions may or may not involve an encounter between the subject and a healthcare
         professional.</originalText>
   </code>
   <code code="DISPACT" codeSystem="2.16.840.1.113883.5.6" displayName="disciplinary action">
      <originalText>Definition: An action taken with respect to a subject Entity by a regulatory or authoritative body with supervisory capacity over
         that entity. The action is taken in response to behavior by the subject Entity that body finds to be undesirable.</originalText>
   </code>
   <code code="EXPOS" codeSystem="2.16.840.1.113883.5.6" displayName="exposure">
      <!-- v:ActClassExposure -->
      <originalText>Definition: An interaction between entities that provides opportunity for transmission of a physical, chemical, or biological
         agent from an exposure source entity to an exposure target entity.</originalText>
   </code>
   <code code="AEXPOS" codeSystem="2.16.840.1.113883.5.6" displayName="acquisition exposure">
      <originalText>Definition: Description:</originalText>
   </code>
   <code code="TEXPOS" codeSystem="2.16.840.1.113883.5.6" displayName="transmission exposure">
      <originalText>Definition: Description:</originalText>
   </code>
   <code code="INC" codeSystem="2.16.840.1.113883.5.6" displayName="incident">
      <originalText>Definition: An event that occurred outside of the control of one or more of the parties involved. Includes the concept of an
         accident.</originalText>
   </code>
   <code code="INFRM" codeSystem="2.16.840.1.113883.5.6" displayName="inform">
      <originalText>Definition: The act of transmitting information and understanding about a topic to a subject where the participation association
         must be SBJ.</originalText>
   </code>
   <code code="INVE" codeSystem="2.16.840.1.113883.5.6" displayName="invoice element">
      <originalText>Definition: Represents concepts related to invoice processing in health care</originalText>
   </code>
   <code code="LIST" codeSystem="2.16.840.1.113883.5.6" displayName="working list">
      <originalText>Definition: Working list collects a dynamic list of individual instances of Act via ActRelationship which reflects the need of an
         individual worker, team of workers, or an organization to manage lists of acts for many different clinical and administrative reasons.
         Examples of working lists include problem lists, goal lists, allergy lists, and to-do lists.</originalText>
   </code>
   <code code="MPROT" codeSystem="2.16.840.1.113883.5.6" displayName="monitoring program">
      <originalText>Definition: An officially or unofficially instituted program to track acts of a particular type or categorization.</originalText>
   </code>
   <code code="OBS" codeSystem="2.16.840.1.113883.5.6" displayName="observation">
      <!-- v:ActClassObservation v:ActClassCompositeOrder v:ActClassProcessStep -->
      <originalText>Definition: Description:An act that is intended to result in new information about a subject. The main difference between
         Observations and other Acts is that Observations have a value attribute. The code attribute of Observation and the value attribute of
         Observation must be considered in combination to determine the semantics of the observation.</originalText>
   </code>
   <code code="ALRT" codeSystem="2.16.840.1.113883.5.6" displayName="detected issue">
      <originalText>Definition: An observation identifying a potential adverse outcome as a result of an Act or combination of Acts.</originalText>
   </code>
   <code code="BATTERY" codeSystem="2.16.840.1.113883.5.6" displayName="battery">
      <originalText>Definition: Definition: An observation that is composed of a set of observations. These observations typically have a logical or
         practical grouping for generally accepted clinical or functional purposes, such as observations that are run together because of automation.
         A battery can define required and optional component observations and, in some cases, will define complex rules that determine whether or not
         a particular observation is made. BATTERY is a constraint on the Observation class in that it is understood to always be composed of
         component observations.</originalText>
   </code>
   <code code="CLNTRL" codeSystem="2.16.840.1.113883.5.6" displayName="clinical trial">
      <originalText>Definition: The set of actions that define an experiment to assess the effectiveness and/or safety of a biopharmaceutical product
         (food, drug, device, etc.). In definition mood, this set of actions is often embodied in a clinical trial protocol; in event mood, this
         designates the aggregate act of applying the actions to one or more subjects.</originalText>
   </code>
   <code code="CNOD" codeSystem="2.16.840.1.113883.5.6" displayName="Condition Node">
      <originalText> Definition:</originalText>
   </code>
   <code code="CONC" codeSystem="2.16.840.1.113883.5.6" displayName="concern">
      <originalText>Definition: Definition: A worry that tends to persist over time and has as its subject a state or process. The subject of the
         worry has the potential to require intervention or management.</originalText>
   </code>
   <code code="COND" codeSystem="2.16.840.1.113883.5.6" displayName="Condition">
      <!-- v:ActClassCondition -->
      <originalText>Definition: An observable finding or state that persists over time and tends to require intervention or management, and,
         therefore, distinguished from an Observation made at a point in time; may exist before an Observation of the Condition is made or after
         interventions to manage the Condition are undertaken. Examples: equipment repair status, device recall status, a health risk, a financial
         risk, public health risk, pregnancy, health maintenance, chronic illness</originalText>
   </code>
   <code code="CASE" codeSystem="2.16.840.1.113883.5.6" displayName="public health case">
      <!-- v:ActClassPublicHealthCase -->
      <originalText>Definition: A public health case is an Observation representing a condition or event that has a specific significance for public
         health. Typically it involves an instance or instances of a reportable infectious disease or other condition. The public health case can
         include a health-related event concerning a single individual or it may refer to multiple health-related events that are occurrences of the
         same disease or condition of interest to public health. An outbreak involving multiple individuals may be considered as a type of public
         health case. A public health case definition (Act.moodCode = "definition") includes the description of the clinical, laboratory, and
         epidemiologic indicators associated with a disease or condition of interest to public health. There are case definitions for conditions that
         are reportable, as well as for those that are not. There are also case definitions for outbreaks. A public health case definition is a
         construct used by public health for the purpose of counting cases, and should not be used as clinical indications for treatment. Examples
         include AIDS, toxic-shock syndrome, and salmonellosis and their associated indicators that are used to define a case.</originalText>
   </code>
   <code code="OUTB" codeSystem="2.16.840.1.113883.5.6" displayName="outbreak">
      <originalText>Definition: An outbreak represents a series of public health cases. The date on which an outbreak starts is the earliest date of
         onset among the cases assigned to the outbreak, and its ending date is the last date of onset among the cases assigned to the
         outbreak.</originalText>
   </code>
   <code code="DGIMG" codeSystem="2.16.840.1.113883.5.6" displayName="diagnostic image">
      <originalText>Definition: Class for holding attributes unique to diagnostic images.</originalText>
   </code>
   <code code="GEN" codeSystem="2.16.840.1.113883.5.6" displayName="genomic observation">
      <!-- v:ActClassGenomicObservation -->
      <originalText>Definition: Description:An observation of genomic phenomena.</originalText>
   </code>
   <code code="DETPOL" codeSystem="2.16.840.1.113883.5.6" displayName="determinant peptide">
      <originalText>Definition: Description:A determinant peptide in a polypeptide as described by polypeptide.</originalText>
   </code>
   <code code="EXP" codeSystem="2.16.840.1.113883.5.6" displayName="expression level">
      <originalText>Definition: Description:An expression level of genes/proteins or other expressed genomic entities.</originalText>
   </code>
   <code code="LOC" codeSystem="2.16.840.1.113883.5.6" displayName="locus">
      <originalText>Definition: Description:The position of a gene (or other significant sequence) on the genome.</originalText>
   </code>
   <code code="PHN" codeSystem="2.16.840.1.113883.5.6" displayName="phenotype">
      <originalText>Definition: Description:A genomic phenomenon that is expressed externally in the organism.</originalText>
   </code>
   <code code="POL" codeSystem="2.16.840.1.113883.5.6" displayName="polypeptide">
      <originalText>Definition: Description:A polypeptide resulting from the translation of a gene.</originalText>
   </code>
   <code code="SEQ" codeSystem="2.16.840.1.113883.5.6" displayName="bio sequence">
      <originalText>Definition: Description:A sequence of biomolecule like the DNA, RNA, protein and the like.</originalText>
   </code>
   <code code="SEQVAR" codeSystem="2.16.840.1.113883.5.6" displayName="bio sequence variation">
      <originalText>Definition: Description:A variation in a sequence as described by BioSequence.</originalText>
   </code>
   <code code="INVSTG" codeSystem="2.16.840.1.113883.5.6" displayName="investigation">
      <originalText>Definition: An formalized inquiry into the circumstances surrounding a particular unplanned event or potential event for the
         purposes of identifying possible causes and contributing factors for the event. This investigation could be conducted at a local
         institutional level or at the level of a local or national government.</originalText>
   </code>
   <code code="OBSSER" codeSystem="2.16.840.1.113883.5.6" displayName="observation series">
      <!-- v:ActClassObservationSeries -->
      <originalText>Definition: Container for Correlated Observation Sequences sharing a common frame of reference. All Observations of the same cd
         must be comparable and relative to the common frame of reference. For example, a 3-channel ECG device records a 12-lead ECG in 4 steps (3
         leads at a time). Each of the separate 3-channel recordings would be in their own "OBSCOR". And, all 4 OBSCOR would be contained in one
         OBSSER because all the times are relative to the same origin (beginning of the recording) and all the ECG signals were from a fixed set of
         electrodes.</originalText>
   </code>
   <code code="OBSCOR" codeSystem="2.16.840.1.113883.5.6" displayName="correlated observation sequences">
      <originalText>Definition: Container for Observation Sequences (Observations whose values are contained in LIST&lt;&gt;'s) having values
         correlated with each other. Each contained Observation Sequence LIST&lt;&gt; must be the same length. Values in the LIST&lt;&gt;'s are
         correlated based on index. E.g. the values in position 2 in all the LIST&lt;&gt;'s are correlated. This is analogous to a table where each
         column is an Observation Sequence with a LIST&lt;&gt; of values, and each row in the table is a correlation between the columns. For example,
         a 12-lead ECG would contain 13 sequences: one sequence for time, and a sequence for each of the 12 leads.</originalText>
   </code>
   <code code="POS" codeSystem="2.16.840.1.113883.5.6" displayName="position">
      <!-- v:ActClassPosition -->
      <originalText>Definition: An observation denoting the physical location of a person or thing based on a reference coordinate
         system.</originalText>
   </code>
   <code code="POSACC" codeSystem="2.16.840.1.113883.5.6" displayName="position accuracy">
      <originalText>Definition: Description:An observation representing the degree to which the assignment of the spatial coordinates, based on a
         matching algorithm by a geocoding engine against a reference spatial database, matches true or accepted values.</originalText>
   </code>
   <code code="POSCOORD" codeSystem="2.16.840.1.113883.5.6" displayName="position coordinate">
      <originalText>Definition: Description:An observation representing one of a set of numerical values used to determine the position of a place.
         The name of the coordinate value is determined by the reference coordinate system.</originalText>
   </code>
   <code code="SPCOBS" codeSystem="2.16.840.1.113883.5.6" displayName="specimen observationActClassSpecObs&#xA;               ">
      <originalText>Definition: An observation on a specimen in a laboratory environment that may affect processing, analysis or result
         interpretation</originalText>
   </code>
   <code code="VERIF" codeSystem="2.16.840.1.113883.5.6" displayName="Verification">
      <originalText>Definition: An act which describes the process whereby a 'verifying party' validates either the existence of the Role attested to
         by some Credential or the actual Vetting act and its details.</originalText>
   </code>
   <!-- 2-A _ActClassROI (v:ActClassROI)-->
   <code code="ROIBND" codeSystem="2.16.840.1.113883.5.6" displayName="bounded ROI">
      <originalText>Definition: A Region of Interest (ROI) specified for a multidimensional observation, such as an Observation Series (OBSSER). The
         ROI is specified using a set of observation criteria, each delineating the boundary of the region in one of the dimensions in the
         multidimensional observation. The relationship between a ROI and its referenced Act is specified through an ActRelationship of type subject
         (SUBJ), which must always be present. Each of the boundary criteria observations is connected with the ROI using ActRelationships of type
         "has component" (COMP). In each boundary criterion, the Act.code names the dimension and the Observation.value specifies the range of values
         inside the region. Typically the bounded dimension is continuous, and so the Observation.value will be an interval (IVL) data type. The
         Observation.value need not be specified if the respective dimension is only named but not constrained. For example, an ROI for the QT
         interval of a certain beat in ECG Lead II would contain 2 boundary criteria, one naming the interval in time (constrained), and the other
         naming the interval in ECG Lead II (only named, but not constrained).</originalText>
   </code>
   <code code="ROIOVL" codeSystem="2.16.840.1.113883.5.6" displayName="overlay ROI">
      <originalText>Definition: A Region of Interest (ROI) specified for an image using an overlay shape. Typically used to make reference to specific
         regions in images, e.g., to specify the location of a radiologic finding in an image or to specify the site of a physical finding by
         "circling" a region in a schematic picture of a human body. The units of the coordinate values are in pixels. The origin is in the upper left
         hand corner, with positive X values going to the right and positive Y values going down. The relationship between a ROI and its referenced
         Act is specified through an ActRelationship of type "subject" (SUBJ), which must always be present.</originalText>
   </code>
   <!-- 2-A _SubjectPhysicalPosition (v:ActClassSubjectPhysicalPosition)-->
   <!-- 3-A _SubjectBodyPosition ()-->
   <code code="LLD" codeSystem="2.16.840.1.113883.5.6" displayName="left lateral decubitus">
      <originalText> Definition:</originalText>
   </code>
   <code code="PRN" codeSystem="2.16.840.1.113883.5.6" displayName="prone">
      <originalText> Definition:</originalText>
   </code>
   <code code="RLD" codeSystem="2.16.840.1.113883.5.6" displayName="right lateral decubitus">
      <originalText> Definition:</originalText>
   </code>
   <code code="SFWL" codeSystem="2.16.840.1.113883.5.6" displayName="Semi-Fowler's">
      <originalText> Definition:</originalText>
   </code>
   <code code="SIT" codeSystem="2.16.840.1.113883.5.6" displayName="sitting">
      <originalText> Definition:</originalText>
   </code>
   <code code="STN" codeSystem="2.16.840.1.113883.5.6" displayName="standing">
      <originalText> Definition:</originalText>
   </code>
   <code code="SUP" codeSystem="2.16.840.1.113883.5.6" displayName="supine">
      <!--  -->
      <originalText> Definition:</originalText>
   </code>
   <code code="RTRD" codeSystem="2.16.840.1.113883.5.6" displayName="reverse trendelenburg">
      <originalText> Definition:</originalText>
   </code>
   <code code="TRD" codeSystem="2.16.840.1.113883.5.6" displayName="trendelenburg">
      <originalText> Definition:</originalText>
   </code>
   <code code="PCPR" codeSystem="2.16.840.1.113883.5.6" displayName="care provision">
      <!-- v:ActClassCareProvision -->
      <originalText>Definition: An Act that of taking on whole or partial responsibility for, or attention to, safety and well-being of a subject of
         care.</originalText>
   </code>
   <code code="ENC" codeSystem="2.16.840.1.113883.5.6" displayName="encounter">
      <originalText>Definition: An interaction between a patient and healthcare participant(s) for the purpose of providing patient service(s) or
         assessing the health status of a patient. For example, outpatient visit to multiple departments, home health support (including physical
         therapy), inpatient hospital stay, emergency room visit, field visit (e.g., traffic accident), office visit, occupational therapy, telephone
         call.</originalText>
   </code>
   <code code="POLICY" codeSystem="2.16.840.1.113883.5.6" displayName="policy">
      <!-- v:ActClassPolicy -->
      <originalText>Definition: Description:A mandate, regulation, obligation, requirement, rule, or expectation unilaterally imposed by one party
         on:</originalText>
   </code>
   <code code="JURISPOL" codeSystem="2.16.840.1.113883.5.6" displayName="jurisdictional policy">
      <originalText>Definition: Description:A mandate, regulation, obligation, requirement, rule, or expectation unilaterally imposed by a
         jurisdiction on:</originalText>
   </code>
   <code code="ORGPOL" codeSystem="2.16.840.1.113883.5.6" displayName="organizational policy">
      <originalText>Definition: Description:A mandate, obligation, requirement, rule, or expectation unilaterally imposed by an organization
         on:</originalText>
   </code>
   <code code="SCOPOL" codeSystem="2.16.840.1.113883.5.6" displayName="scope of practice policy">
      <originalText>Definition: Description:An ethical or clinical obligation, requirement, rule, or expectation imposed or strongly encouraged by
         organizations that oversee particular clinical domains or provider certification which define the boundaries within which a provider may
         practice and which may have legal basis or ramifications on:</originalText>
   </code>
   <code code="STDPOL" codeSystem="2.16.840.1.113883.5.6" displayName="standard of practice policy">
      <originalText>Definition: Description:A requirement, rule, or expectation typically documented as guidelines, protocols, or formularies imposed
         or strongly encouraged by an organization that oversees or has authority over the practices within a domain, and which may have legal basis
         or ramifications on:</originalText>
   </code>
   <code code="PROC" codeSystem="2.16.840.1.113883.5.6" displayName="procedure">
      <!-- v:ActClassProcedure v:ActClassCompositeOrder v:ActClassProcessStep -->
      <originalText>Definition: An Act whose immediate and primary outcome (post-condition) is the alteration of the physical condition of the
         subject.</originalText>
   </code>
   <code code="SBADM" codeSystem="2.16.840.1.113883.5.6" displayName="substance administration">
      <originalText>Definition: The act of introducing or otherwise applying a substance to the subject.</originalText>
   </code>
   <code code="SBEXT" codeSystem="2.16.840.1.113883.5.6" displayName="Substance Extraction">
      <!-- v:ActClassSubstanceExtraction -->
      <originalText>Definition: Description: The act of removing a substance from the subject.</originalText>
   </code>
   <code code="SPECCOLLECT" codeSystem="2.16.840.1.113883.5.6" displayName="Specimen Collection">
      <originalText>Definition: A procedure for obtaining a specimen from a source entity.</originalText>
   </code>
   <code code="REG" codeSystem="2.16.840.1.113883.5.6" displayName="registration">
      <originalText>Definition: Represents the act of maintaining information about the registration of its associated registered subject. The subject
         can be either an Act or a Role, and includes subjects such as lab exam definitions, drug protocol definitions, prescriptions, persons,
         patients, practitioners, and equipment.</originalText>
   </code>
   <code code="REV" codeSystem="2.16.840.1.113883.5.6" displayName="review">
      <originalText>Definition: The act of examining and evaluating the subject, usually another act. For example, "This prescription needs to be
         reviewed in 2 months."</originalText>
   </code>
   <code code="SPCTRT" codeSystem="2.16.840.1.113883.5.6" displayName="specimen treatment">
      <originalText>Definition: A procedure or treatment performed on a specimen to prepare it for analysis</originalText>
   </code>
   <code code="SPLY" codeSystem="2.16.840.1.113883.5.6" displayName="supply">
      <!-- v:ActClassSupply v:ActClassCompositeOrder -->
      <originalText>Definition: Supply orders and deliveries are simple Acts that focus on the delivered product. The product is associated with the
         Supply Act via Participation.typeCode="product". With general Supply Acts, the precise identification of the Material (manufacturer, serial
         numbers, etc.) is important. Most of the detailed information about the Supply should be represented using the Material class. If delivery
         needs to be scheduled, tracked, and billed separately, one can associate a Transportation Act with the Supply Act. Pharmacy dispense services
         are represented as Supply Acts, associated with a SubstanceAdministration Act. The SubstanceAdministration class represents the
         administration of medication, while dispensing is supply.</originalText>
   </code>
   <code code="DIET" codeSystem="2.16.840.1.113883.5.6" displayName="diet">
      <originalText> Definition:</originalText>
   </code>
   <code code="STORE" codeSystem="2.16.840.1.113883.5.6" displayName="storage">
      <originalText>Definition: The act of putting something away for safe keeping. The "something" may be physical object such as a specimen, or
         information, such as observations regarding a specimen.</originalText>
   </code>
   <code code="SUBST" codeSystem="2.16.840.1.113883.5.6" displayName="Substitution">
      <originalText>Definition: Definition: Indicates that the subject Act has undergone or should undergo substitution of a type indicated by
         Act.code.</originalText>
   </code>
   <code code="TRFR" codeSystem="2.16.840.1.113883.5.6" displayName="transfer">
      <originalText>Definition: Definition: The act of transferring information without the intent of imparting understanding about a topic to the
         subject that is the recipient or holder of the transferred information where the participation association must be RCV or HLD.</originalText>
   </code>
   <code code="TRNS" codeSystem="2.16.840.1.113883.5.6" displayName="transportation">
      <originalText>Definition: Transportation is the moving of a payload (people or material) from a location of origin to a destination location.
         Thus, any transport service has the three target instances of type payload, origin, and destination, besides the targets that are generally
         used for any service (i.e., performer, device, etc.)</originalText>
   </code>
   <code code="XACT" codeSystem="2.16.840.1.113883.5.6" displayName="financial transaction">
      <originalText>Definition: A sub-class of Act representing any transaction between two accounts whose value is measured in monetary
         terms.</originalText>
   </code>
   <!-- 1-A _ActClassRecordOrganizer (v:ActClassRecordOrganizer)-->
   <code code="COMPOSITION" codeSystem="2.16.840.1.113883.5.6" displayName="compositionAttestable unit&#xA;               ">
      <!-- v:ActClassComposition -->
      <originalText>Definition: A context representing a grouped commitment of information to the EHR. It is considered the unit of modification of
         the record, the unit of transmission in record extracts, and the unit of attestation by authorizing clinicians.</originalText>
   </code>
   <code code="DOC" codeSystem="2.16.840.1.113883.5.6" displayName="document">
      <!-- v:ActClassDocument -->
      <originalText>Definition: The notion of a document comes particularly from the paper world, where it corresponds to the contents recorded on
         discrete pieces of paper. In the electronic world, a document is a kind of composition that bears resemblance to their paper world
         counter-parts. Documents typically are meant to be human-readable.</originalText>
   </code>
   <code code="DOCCLIN" codeSystem="2.16.840.1.113883.5.6" displayName="clinical document">
      <!-- v:ActClassClinicalDocument -->
      <originalText>Definition: A clinical document is a documentation of clinical observations and services, with the following
         characteristics:</originalText>
   </code>
   <code code="CDALVLONE" codeSystem="2.16.840.1.113883.5.6" displayName="CDA Level One clinical document">
      <originalText>Definition: A clinical document that conforms to Level One of the HL7 Clinical Document Architecture (CDA)</originalText>
   </code>
   <code code="CONTAINER" codeSystem="2.16.840.1.113883.5.6" displayName="record container">
      <!-- v:ActClassContainer -->
      <originalText>Definition: Description: Container of clinical statements. Navigational. No semantic content. Knowledge of the section code is not
         required to interpret contained observations. Represents a heading in a heading structure, or "container tree".</originalText>
   </code>
   <code code="CATEGORY" codeSystem="2.16.840.1.113883.5.6" displayName="category">
      <originalText>Definition: A group of entries within a composition or topic that have a common characteristic - for example, Examination,
         Diagnosis, Management OR Subjective, Objective, Analysis, Plan.</originalText>
   </code>
   <code code="DOCBODY" codeSystem="2.16.840.1.113883.5.6" displayName="document body">
      <originalText>Definition: A context that distinguishes the body of a document from the document header. This is seen, for instance, in HTML
         documents, which have discrete &lt;head&gt; and &lt;body&gt; elements.</originalText>
   </code>
   <code code="DOCSECT" codeSystem="2.16.840.1.113883.5.6" displayName="document sectionSection&#xA;               ">
      <originalText>Definition: A context that subdivides the body of a document. Document sections are typically used for human navigation, to give a
         reader a clue as to the expected content. Document sections are used to organize and provide consistency to the contents of a document body.
         Document sections can contain document sections and can contain entries.</originalText>
   </code>
   <code code="TOPIC" codeSystem="2.16.840.1.113883.5.6" displayName="topic">
      <originalText>Definition: A group of entries within a composition that are related to a common clinical theme - such as a specific disorder or
         problem, prevention, screening and provision of contraceptive services.</originalText>
   </code>
   <code code="EXTRACT" codeSystem="2.16.840.1.113883.5.6" displayName="extract">
      <!-- v:ActClassExtract -->
      <originalText>Definition: This context represents the part of a patient record conveyed in a single communication. It is drawn from a providing
         system for the purposes of communication to a requesting process (which might be another repository, a client application or a middleware
         service such as an electronic guideline engine), and supporting the faithful inclusion of the communicated data in the receiving
         system.</originalText>
   </code>
   <code code="EHR" codeSystem="2.16.840.1.113883.5.6" displayName="electronic health record">
      <originalText>Definition: A context that comprises all compositions. The EHR is an extract that includes the entire chart.</originalText>
   </code>
   <code code="FOLDER" codeSystem="2.16.840.1.113883.5.6" displayName="folder">
      <originalText>Definition: A context representing the high-level organization of an extract e.g. to group parts of the record by episode, care
         team, clinical specialty, clinical condition, or source application. Internationally, this kind of organizing structure is used variably: in
         some centers and systems the folder is treated as an informal compartmentalization of the overall health record; in others it might represent
         a significant legal portion of the EHR relating to the originating enterprise or team.</originalText>
   </code>
   <code code="GROUPER" codeSystem="2.16.840.1.113883.5.6" displayName="grouper">
      <!-- v:ActClassGrouper v:ActClassCompositeOrder -->
      <originalText>Definition: Definition: An ACT that organizes a set of component acts into a semantic grouping that share a particular context
         such as timeframe, patient, etc.</originalText>
   </code>
   <code code="CLUSTER" codeSystem="2.16.840.1.113883.5.6" displayName="Cluster">
      <originalText>Definition: Description:An ACT that organizes a set of component acts into a semantic grouping that have a shared subject. The
         subject may be either a subject participation (SBJ), subject act relationship (SUBJ), or child participation/act relationship
         types.</originalText>
   </code>
</codeSystem>
